

### **About**

I'm a pragmatic Software Engineer living at the intersection of design, user experience and engineering. I believe in crafting maintainable, scalable and performant products that delight users and satisfy the unique needs of your business. I specialize full-stack JavaScript development and the mobile web.

# **Experience**

Sr. Software Engineer, Engineering Team Lead @ Squarespace 07/2020 - Present • New York, NY • squarespace.com

Senior Engineer & Team Lead for Conversion at Squarespace. Managed team & technical direction for all projects. Responsible for coordinating with product & design to translate complex user stories into structured engineering roadmaps.

Software Engineer @ Squarespace

12/2018 - 07/2020 • New York, NY • squarespace.com

Member of the Trial Experience team at Squarespace. Responsible for measurably improving product conversion rate by reducing friction points during user onboarding and trial. Primarily worked in TypeScript, React, Redux & Apollo Client.

Frontend Engineer @ Reserve Media

06/2017 - 11/2018 • New York, NY • reserve.com • acquired by Resy 11/18

Engineered the frontend for all Reserve web products. Rebuilt consumer platform with focus on mobile performance, resulting in a 6x improvement to page load time. Drastically improved browser compatibility  $\theta$  increased user reservation rates.

 ${\bf Mobile\ Web\ Team\ Lead\ @\ Forbes\ Magazine}$ 

04/2015 - 06/2017 • Jersey City, NJ • forbes.com

Shipped improvements to Forbes.com, enhancing the web experience for 10 million monthly users. Lead dev on new mobile-optimized article experience resulting in 3x increase in engagement  $\delta$  50% increase in time on page.

Web Applications Developer @ Rochester Institute of Technology 08/2013 - 01/2015 • Rochester, NY ● rit.edu/asc/online

Sole student developer overseeing the maintenance, expansion  $\vartheta$  rebranding of dozens of web apps under the Student Academic Support Center. Collaborated with Students and Faculty to create ad-hoc web solutions to meet department needs.

Fullstack Developer Internship @ Magnani Caruso Dutton

06/2014 - 08/2014 • New York, NY • mcdpartners.com

Sole fullstack developer for internal expense reporting platform used by MCD employees. Developed single page promotional experiences for clients including Samsung, Discover Financial, and HBO.

#### **Education**

B.Sc, New Media Interactive Development 2010 - 2014 • Rochester, New York • 3.55 GPA

College of Computing and Information Sciences Rochester Institute of Technology. Minor, Literature Studies

#### Contact

tom@thomasconroy.net https://conroy.codes

### Languages

- JavaScript (ES6+)
- NodeJS
- TypeScript
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- GraphQL (Relay, Apollo)

#### Client-Side

- React
- Preact
- AngularJS
- Vue.js

- Redux

- Express
- React Native
- ImmutableJS
- ServiceWorkers
- Styled Components

### Server-Side

- Express
- NestJS
- TypeORM
- Laravel
- Apollo Server / GraphQL
- LoopBack
- Sequelize

### **Tooling**

- SCM (git)
- Unix (Bash/ZSH)
- Webpack, Gulp, Parcel
- SASS, LESS
- TypeScript
- Docke
- Sketch, Figma, Adobe CS

# **Methodologies**

- Agile (scrum)
- Test-Driven Development
- mobile-first development (RWD)
- Hypothesis Driven Development
- A/B Testina

# Social







in thomasconroy